♪ 我的爱无始 ♪
♪ My love has no beginning ♪
♪ 也无终 ♪
♪ My love has no end ♪
♪ 没有过去也没有未来 它不会摇摆 ♪
♪ No front or back, and my love won't bend ♪
♪ 而我就在这里 ♪
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪ 迷失在它的涡旋中 ♪
♪ Lost in a spin ♪
♪ 我爱你... ♪
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪ 而你却不知道 ♪
♪ And you don't know ♪
♪ 你不知道 你不知道 你不知道 ♪
♪ You don't know, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ 我有多么高兴
♪ How glad I am
♪ 我的爱没有上限也没有下限 ♪
♪ My love has no bottom, my love has no top ♪
♪ 不增也不减 ♪
♪ My love won't rise, and my love won't drop ♪
♪ 我就在这里 ♪
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪ 无法停止
♪ And I can't stop
♪ 爱你... ♪
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪ 而你不知道 你不知道 你不知道 ♪
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ 你不知道我有多高兴 ♪
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪ 我希望我是个诗人 ♪
♪ I wish I were a poet ♪
♪ 这样我就能说出 ♪
♪ So I could express ♪
♪ 我想说的 ♪
♪ What I'd like to say, yeah ♪
♪ 我希望我是一名艺术家 ♪
♪ I wish I were an artist ♪
♪ 这样我就可以画出 ♪
♪ So I could paint a picture ♪
♪ 我今天的感受 ♪
♪ Of how I feel today, yeah ♪
♪ 我的爱没有界限 ♪
♪ My love has no walls on either side ♪
♪ 这会让我的爱更加喷薄 ♪
♪ That makes my love wider than wide ♪
♪ 我就在那里 ♪
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪ 无处躲藏 ♪
♪ And I can't hide ♪
♪ 我爱你... ♪
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪ 而你不知道 你不知道 你不知道 ♪
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪ 你不知道我有多高兴 ♪
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪ 我有多么高兴
♪ How glad I am
♪ 我有多么高兴...
♪ How glad I am...
艾琳
Eileen.
Eileen!
我需要I-37那张表格
I need form I-37.
- 调任书吗 - 不是
- Transfer form? - No.
入职的那张 I-37
Intake. I-37.
你有在听吗
Aren't you listening?
她真没用
She is useless.
还需要弗莱医生的签字
Dr. Frye still needs to sign it.
但是他可能在办公室里睡着了
He's probably asleep in his office.
至少你能去叫醒弗莱医生吧
Maybe you could go wake up Dr. Frye.
在他耳边轻轻吹口气
Blow softly in his ear.
他就喜欢这样
He loves that.
让她一个人待会儿吧
Leave Eileen alone.
她看起来很累
She's tired.
哦 是这样吗
Oh, is that what it is?
可能是每个月的那个日子来了
I thought maybe it was that time of the month.
至少我是这样的
At least I have a time of the month.
对了 你知道吗 亲爱的
Oh, yeah. You know something, honey?
这不会永远持续下去的 很快你就跟我们一样老了
It won't last forever. You'll be old like us soon.
请纳尔逊夫人到拜访区
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area, please.
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area.
请纳尔逊夫人到拜访区
我不会和任何人打架 我跟你说了
I'm not gonna fight with anybody. I told you.
米奇怎么样
How's Mickey doing?
我已经在努力变好了
I'm trying to be good.
坐下 坐下 坐下
Sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
这不是我的错...
Well, it's not my fault...
我还是下次再来吧
Maybe I'll see you next time.
尽管我们都会怀念这个老家伙
As much as we're gonna miss the old dog,
但是我还是希望下周一大家能热情欢迎
I hope you'll all be welcoming
弗莱医生的继任者
to Dr. Frye's replacement on Monday.
一位优秀的年轻医生
A fine, fine young doctor.
希望男孩们都能认真对待她
Yes, well, let's hope the boys take her seriously.
我会的
I'll take her.
真的吗
Seriously.
我想你会带上你的胰岛素
I think you will be taking your insulin
还有退休金
and your retirement package.
这两样就够了吧
That'll be enough for you.
没错
That's right.
我会怀念你们的
I'll really miss all the fun around here.
为弗莱医生鼓掌
Let's hear it for Dr. Frye.
干杯
Cheers!
最近好多人都点安妮酒啊
I see a lot of Anne these days.
是啊 外面有很多伤心人
Yeah, a lot of broken hearts out there.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, hon.
嘿
Hey.
你爸爸怎么样了
How's your dad?
挺好的
Good.
还是我来吧
You know what? Let me get that.
谢谢
Thanks.
...你他妈的赶紧闭嘴吧
...want you to go inside and shut the fuck up!
你才…你才闭嘴
You shut... you shut up!
滚蛋 住口 你闭嘴
Fuck off! Shut up! You shut up!
哦 臭酒鬼 我会...
Fucking booze bag! Oh, I'll do...
- 我还要再喝一杯  - 嘿 你还好吗
- I'm gonna have a drink. - You all right there, chief?
你可以滚了
You can fuck right off.
都是因为隔壁那个该死的路德教徒 不是我
Goddamn Lutherans next door are the problem, not me.
没有人说你 我们只是想确保
Nobody's complaining. We just want to make sure
你能安然无恙地到家
you're getting home safe and sound.
没人吗 啊
Nobody's complaining?
- 爸爸  - 狗屁安然无恙
- Dad. - Safe and sound?
我还能出什么事儿吗
Why wouldn't I be safe and sound?
爸
Dad.
整个社区的安全我都有责任
I keep the whole fucking neighborhood safe and sound.
- 你知道个屁 - 爸爸
- What do you know? - Dad.
艾...艾琳 进去吧
E-Eileen, go inside.
- 好啊 爸爸 你看着我 - 进去吧
- Okay. Dad, look to me. - Go inside.
快点 拜托了
Come on. Please. Please.
嘿 你这是在闹事
Hey! You're causing a scene.
相信我 艾琳 没有人会别无所图地跟你在一起
Trust me, Eileen. Nobody wants nothing with you.
- 好的 - 哇
- Okay. - Mwah!
- 快点 进去  - 哇
- Come on. Go inside. - Mwah!
那些该死的路德教徒就在那里
Goddamn Lutherans right there.
你妈妈一直讨厌那些人
Your mother always hated those people.
- 天哪 我们快进去吧  - 他们可以滚了 就这么定了
- Gosh, let's go inside. - They can fuck off. Sure.
你不能到处去管别人 爸爸
You can't go around policing people, Dad.
谁说的 你知道是哪个人说的吗
Who says? You know who that guy was?
一切都在掌控之中 长官
We got it all under control, chief.
你不用这么紧张
You can take it easy. Please.
还别紧张 你他妈的敢松懈吗
Take it easy? Y-You fuckin' take it easy.
你已经不是警察了
You're not a cop anymore.
好啊  你说的对
Yeah, sure.
我不想退休 都是他们干的
I didn't want to retire. They made me,
一定是因为我太优秀了
'cause I was too goddamn good at it.
听着 我得回去了
Look, I gotta get back to the station.
给我倒杯喝的
Pour me a drink. Good.
回去吧 巴克
Get back to the station, Buck.
把喝的给我
Give me my drink.
如果你还需要什么 就给我们打电话
Just give us a call if you need anything.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
嘿 你过来 那是什么味道
Hey, come here. What's that smell?
你有踩到什么东西吗
Did you step in something?
没有 为什么这么问 你是闻到什么味道了吗
No. Why? What do you smell?
我不知道 像是踩到了路边被撞死的动物
I don't know. Roadkill.
也许你得保持点儿距离
Maybe you should keep your distance.
我知道了
Yeah, I'll keep my distance.
你他妈在搞什么 把我的鞋给我穿回去
The fuck you doing? Put my fucking shoes back on.
但是你是不是得对我好点儿
But maybe you should be nicer to me.
没人能忍受得了你这样
No one else is gonna put up with your shit.
那你就走吧 我还有乔·安妮呢
Go then, 'cause I got Joanie.
她才不会让家里变成这样
She wouldn't keep a place looking like this.
你妹妹是个真正的女人
She's a real woman, your sister.
味道也不像你
And she smells like a woman.
她知道怎么持家
She knows how to keep a house!
但是她不住在这里 而且她已经结婚了
And she doesn't live here, and she's married!
是啊 她也不会在这里蹭吃蹭喝
Yeah, 'cause she's not a hanger-on.
你怎么不说她都不想跟你说话
And she doesn't want to talk to you!
是啊 那是因为她有自己的生活
Yeah, sure, 'cause she's made a life of her own.
也有自己的事情要忙
She's made something of herself.
无所谓了 爸爸
Whatever, Dad.
好好生活吧 艾琳 别这么混下去了
Get a life, Eileen. Get a clue.
妈的
Shit.
滚吧
Fuck it.
好了 听着
All right, listen up!
你们都知道了 今年
As you know, in the new year,
我们要接受审查
we will be up for state review.
所以我们要加强我们的规程管理
So we're gonna be tightening our procedures
同时基于一些不错的想法实施新的计划
and implementing new strategies based on some big, new ideas.
说到这里 我左边的这位新来的年轻的女士
And on that note, this new young lady to my left,
瑞贝卡·圣约翰
Dr. Miss Rebecca St. John,
是我们新来的监狱心理学家
is our new prison psychologist.
她刚在拉德克利夫读完博士学位
She's just finished her doctorate at Radcliffe.
哈佛
Harvard.
啊 哈佛
Ah. Harvard.
我们可能不是哈佛人
We may not be Harvard people,
但我觉得我们可以跟上她的步伐
but I think we can keep up with her,
同时也希望她还有我们大家
and hopefully she can keep up with us
都能保持同样的节奏
as we keep up with them.
她可能看起来很讨人喜欢 但我向你们保证
She may be easy on the eyes, but I assure you,
她同时也非常聪明
she is very smart.
女士们 我希望你们带圣约翰小姐四处看看…
Ladies, I hope you show Miss St. John around...
所以这得多少钱
Say, how much for a glazed?
是免费的
They're free.
开玩笑啦
I'm kidding.
我是瑞贝卡
I'm Rebecca.
我知道
I know.
话说 梳妆的地方在哪里呢
Say, where can a girl get freshened up around here?
我带你去
I can show you.
多谢啦
Sure. Appreciate it.
我可以帮你拿着夹克
Can I take your jacket?
太贴心了 谢谢
Aren't you sweet? Thanks.
这边
This way.
你有说过自己的名字吗
I don't think I caught your name.
艾琳
Eileen.
- 早 - 早
- Morning. - Morning.
你是从哪儿来的
Where you from?
什么
Huh?
哦 纽约
Oh, I'm from New York originally.
曼哈顿
Manhattan.
我受不了剑桥 那里的人太保守了
Couldn't stand Cambridge. Way too uptight.
倒是有几个有意思的人
Well, there were a couple of interesting people,
但是我还是觉得自己需要休息休息
but, no, I needed a break.
呼吸点儿新鲜的空气
Get some fresh air.
我喜欢海滩
And I love the beach.
好了
All right.
32...
24...
...34
...34.
是我的三围
Practically my measurements.
你知道 有些女性会觉得自己的身材
You know, some women think their figures
才是唯一重要的事情
are the only thing that matters.
老实说 我觉得这有点可悲
Honestly, I think that's kind of pathetic.
完全同意
I completely agree.
我姐姐就是这样 而且她也没有很时髦
My sister's like that, and she's not very smart.
那很好 这样你和我
Mm, good. Then you and I
除了这些就有更好的趣事儿可以聊了
have better things to discuss than our figures.
虽然都不是些主流的话题
Although that isn't the popular opinion,
你说呢
wouldn't you say?
我才不在乎流行什么呢
I don't care what's popular.
好吧 看看你
Well, look at you.
活脱脱一个日常的凯瑟琳·赫本
A regular Katharine Hepburn.
我真的很少见到这么有进取心的年轻的女孩子
Rare to meet a young woman with so much gumption.
我也是这样的
I'm like that, too.
不在乎人们的想法
I don't give a rat's ass what people think.
他们可能会更害怕你
They're probably scared of you.
我吗
Moi?
好的 回头见
All right. See you around.
每年
Every year,
我们都会举行这次特别的集会
we hold this special assembly
来庆祝我主耶稣基督的诞生
to celebrate the birth of Our Lord Jesus Christ.
但是每一年 你们这些混蛋里的某个人
And every year, one of you sick bastards
都会给我搞砸
ruins it for the rest of us.
但是这种事情今年就不会再发生了
Well, you've disrespected Christmas for the last time
因为今年 你们都得闭上嘴
because this year, you're gonna sit on your hands,
好好坐着
you're gonna zip your lips.
如果我看到你们中间有人闹事的话
If I see any of you biting, kicking, screaming, pushing,
不管是什么
pulling hair, laughing, moaning,
或者让我听到任何一句任性的评论
or I hear one wayward comment,
都会直接被我关禁闭
you're going straight to the cave.
现在 话不多说
And now, without further ado,
我很荣幸向橄榄山的人们表达感谢
it is my honor to thank the people from Mount Olive
今年多亏了他们的帮助…
who helped me direct the pageant again this year...
- 耶 橄榄山 - 才能把这出表演带给你们
- Yay, Mount Olive. - and present to you
欢迎欣赏 监狱里的圣诞节
"Christmas in Prison."
我要在圣诞节杀个人
I'm gonna kill someone on Christmas.
住口
Shut up!
哦 我该怎么办
Oh, what am I to do?
三年的牢狱
Sentenced for three years to sit indoors
跟那些和我有一样的信仰的男孩儿们在一起 真的是太糟了
among boys of my same creed, plain bad.
不过现在有这么多时间来策划
So much time to plot
等我出去之后做什么坏事儿
what evildoings I'll undertake as soon as I get out.
要吃蛋糕吗 你这个胖子
You want some cake, you fatty?!
或者我可以读本书
In the meantime, I suppose I could read a book.
你会读吗 混蛋
You can't read, motherfucker!
你妈的莎士比亚就在下面坐着呢
Fucking Shakespeare up here.
我现在很烦躁
I'm scrappy right now.
真理之书
Book of truth!
哦 看看麦卡利斯特
Oh, look at McAllister.
他妈的是麦卡利斯特
Fucking McAllister.
嘿 挺不错的啊
Hey, nice rack!
嗯 我...我好累
Well, I'm-I'm pretty tired.
我们可以在外面的谷仓里休息吗
Can we rest in that barn over there?
比付钱住旅馆更好
Better than paying for a motel.
你是最棒的 约瑟夫
You're the best, Joseph.
谢谢你带我们来参加人口普查
Thank you for taking us here to be counted in the census.
他妈的狗屎
Fuck this shit!
警卫 等等
Guard! Wait.
嘿 抓住他
Wait. Wait, wait. Hey, grab him.
后退
Move back!
都坐下
All you guys sit down!
他妈的坐下
Sit the fuck down!
嘿 鲍勃
Hey, Bob.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, hon.
这个还有一包幸运牌香烟
This and a pack of Luckies.
真是幸运的一天 是吧
Oh! It's a lucky day, huh?
是的 最幸运的一天
Yeah, the luckiest.
是的 那些香烟很棒
Yup. Cigarettes are great.
别烧着自己了
Don't light yourself on fire.
你心情挺不错的 怎么了
You're in a good mood, what's wrong with you?
没什么 爸爸
Nothing's wrong, Dad.
你叼着烟看起来挺蠢的
You look funny with that thing in your mouth.
你今天怎么样啊 爸爸
How was your day, Dad?
我吗
How was my day?
不知道
I don't know.
一天又一天的
It was a day, just another day.
没什么区别
What's the point?
我今天过得挺充实的
My day was a doozy.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
圣诞节庆典上有人打起来了
A big fight broke out at the Christmas pageant.
有个孩子骨折了
Kid got his collarbone broken,
我得为典狱长做这些文书工作
and I had to do all this paperwork for the warden.
别把烟灰抖在地上 会发粘
Don't ash on the floor, it's tacky.
反正...
Anyway...
是个永远都不会忘记的一天
It was one of those days you never forget.
是吗 我想想看
Oh, yeah? Days I'll never forget.
那些我永远都不会忘记的日子
Let me see.
1944 年 12 月 16 日
December 16, 1944,
我第一次把死人的头抱在腿上
first time I ever held a dead man's head in my lap.
真是浪费啊
What a waste.
外面20度 正在下雪
20 degrees outside and snowing.
就像这里一样
Just like it is here.
我也不知道自己为什么又回到了这个地方
Don't know why I ever came back to this place.
也许是因为你有老婆和两个孩子
Maybe because you had a wife and two kids.
或许吧
Maybe.
我喜欢海滩
I love the beach.
是吗 真为你高兴
Oh, yeah? Good for you.
那些战争已经毁了我对海滩的好感
War kind of ruined beaches for me.
还有什么
So what else?
那个波尔克小子怎么样 他招了吗
How's that Polk kid? He talked yet?
什么
Huh?
波尔克
Polk.
那个刺伤父亲的孩子...
The kid who stabbed his father...
...他爸怎么说也算是个好警察
...who was a good cop, more or less.
什么样的孩子会想着像这样杀死自己的父亲呢
What kind of kid thinks of killing his father like that?
趁他睡着的时候捅他一刀……
Stab him in his sleep...
还是在他母亲面前
in front of his mother.
他就那么坐下了
Then he just sits down.
什么也不否认
Never denies it.
整个审判过程中一句话也不说
Never says a word the whole trial.
神经病一样
Psychopathic.
我当然不用担心你
Course I wouldn't have to worry about you
会做那样的事 我需要担心吗
doing something like that, now, would I?
你是个女孩
'Cause you're a girl.
我都想象不出来你拿着刀的样子
Can't imagine you with a knife.
那你能想象出来我拿着枪吗
Can you imagine me with a gun?
我只能看见...
Yeah, I can see it.
也许有一天...
One day...
当你受够了 感觉 呃...
when you've had enough and you feel like, uh...
想要悄悄溜走
ducking out.
也可能是我死了之后
Maybe when I'm dead and gone
你身边什么人也没有 而且是永远
and you got nobody and you never will.
我可以想象到那个
I could imagine that.
但你不会 对吗
But you wouldn't, would you?
因为你太优秀了
'Cause you're too good.
行了 给我一根香烟
Say, give me one of those cigarettes.
你抽的是什么 老金吗
What have you got, Old Gold?
不是
No.
我更喜欢那个
I like Old Gold.
我知道
I know.
诶
Oopsie.
需要帮忙吗
Do you need any help?
额 不用 没啥事儿
Uh, no, I'm okay.
就是没拿稳东西
Just butterfingers.
你真应该看看我
You should see me.
我是个十足的笨蛋
I'm a total klutz.
啊 是这个
Oh, right.
李·波尔克
Lee Polk.
这可不是你每天都能看到的
That's not something you see every day.
是啊 真的影响很不好
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
怎么 睡前读物吗
Bedtime reading?
不是 就是在归档
I was just doing some filing.
是因为昨天的那场好戏吗
That's some show yesterday.
他们每年都会那样
They do it every year.
我认为这是残酷且不寻常的惩罚
I'd call that cruel and unusual punishment.
对不起 我一般不抽烟
Sorry. I don't usually smoke.
确实是个令人讨厌的习惯
It's a nasty habit.
所以我才喜欢它
That's why I like it.
虽然看上去不太像是个淑女就是了
Not very becoming of a lady, though.
会让牙齿变黄
Turns your teeth yellow.
看到了没
See?
都是因为香烟和咖啡
That's cigarettes and coffee.
还有红酒
And red wine.
不 你的牙齿很完美
No, your teeth are perfect.
我不喝咖啡
I don't drink coffee,
所以我的牙齿应该没什么问题的 但是…
so my teeth should be fine, but...
…它们也都蛀了
...they're all rotted
因为我非常喜欢甜食
due to my extreme propensity for sweets.
哈 喜欢吃甜食吗
A propensity for sweets.
你的生活给不了你那些甜分吗
You don't get enough sweetness in your life?
我只是会吃很多糖果
I just eat a lot of candy.
嗯嗯 我可看不出来
Mm. I wouldn't know it to look at you.
你还蛮较小的
You're so petite.
当然 身高也有它的优势
Being tall has its advantages, of course,
但大多数男人对我来说都太矮了
but most men are just too short for me.
你没有注意到 还是说都是我想象的
Have you noticed, or am I imagining things,
现在的男人越来越矮了
that men these days are getting shorter and shorter,
又秃又胖
balder, and fatter?
可是这里的男人可都是些小男孩
All the men around here are little boys.
真幽默
You're funny.
我说的是外面的男人
I meant outside this prison.
虽然你说得对
Although you're right.
警卫们 监狱长
The guards, the warden,
都没什么看头
they're not much to look at.
你真应该去看看弗莱医生
You should have seen Dr. Frye.
他的确是非常难看了
He was really pretty nasty looking.
一点儿也不惊讶
That doesn't surprise me.
我的办公室真的让人很不适应
My office isn't very becoming,
到处都是脏皮革的味道
and it all smells of dirty leather.
我开始想知道里面都发生过什么了
I'm beginning to wonder what went on in there.
没什么好事儿就是了
Nothing good.
别误会 我也从来没进去过
I mean, I never actually been in that office.
哦 那你应该找个时间过来坐坐
Oh. Well, you should come by sometime.
如果门关着的话
Although if the door's closed,
那就说明我正在跟这里的某个男孩儿谈话
that means I'm with one of the boys.
好的
Okay.
你从来都没害怕过吗
Aren't you ever scared
跟他们独处一室
being alone in there with them?
没什么好怕的
No.
有时间就来找我 好吗
Come by, and see me sometime, all right?
不过 如果你听到我在尖叫的话
Although, you know, if you hear me screaming in there,
别犹豫 马上踹开门来救我
feel free to kick down the door and rescue me.
好的
Okay.
我只是开玩笑 亲爱的
I'm just kidding, honey.
有警报器呢
There's a buzzer.
我是来见伦纳德·波尔克的
I'm here to see Leonard Polk.
安妮·波尔克.
Anne Polk.
登记表上没有你的名字
You're not on the schedule.
是后补的吗
Are you a late addition?
是有人通知我的
I-I was called.
我也不懂 反正我就来了
I don't know, I-I'm here now.
嗯 那你需要填一张表格
Well, you need to fill out a form.
你不是邓洛普局长的孩子吗
Aren't you Chief Dunlop's kid?
是的
Yeah.
我说呢
I thought so.
波尔克夫人 我是圣约翰医生
Mrs. Polk? I'm Dr. St. John.
我们讲过电话的 很高兴你来了
We spoke on the phone. Thank you so much for coming.
哦 这就算了
Oh, no need to bother with that.
我们都知道你是谁
We all know who you are.
艾琳 你能帮我们开下门吗
Eileen, would you help us with the door?
谢谢
Thank you.
这边来
It's this way.
别忘记外套了
Take your coat?
请
Please.
谢谢你 艾琳
Thank you, Eileen.
您先请
After you.
你为什么要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
啊
Huh?
你有话要对我说吗
You got something to say to me?
让我出去
Let me out!
让我出去 让我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
让我出去
Let me out!
你们想怎么处置他都行
Y-You do... y'all do what you want with him.
连自己的母亲都不肯说吗
Won't even talk to his own mother?
他一直是个令人讨厌的孩子
He's always been a nasty boy.
又脏又坏的小子
A filthy, nasty boy!
我得锁起来了
I need to lock up.
探视时间实际上已经过了20多分钟了
Visitation hours were actually over 20 minutes ago.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I-I understand.
你想在我办公室继续聊吗
Would you like to keep talking in my office?
- 我们走吧 - 转身
- Let's go. - Turn around.
不用了 没必要
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
- 我需要给他戴上手铐 - 不用
- I need to cuff him. - No.
别担心 李 没关系的
Don't worry, Lee. It's all right.
说什么没必要
That won't be necessary.
别这样 她才是医生
Don't do that. She's a doctor.
我看她才是需要个医生
I think she needs a doctor.
那孩子杀了一名警察
That kid killed a cop.
他杀了他的父亲
He killed his father.
那还是有区别的
There's a difference.
哦 真的抱歉 我去看看是谁
Oh, I'm so sorry. Let me see who it is.
哦 艾琳啊
Oh, Eileen.
怎么了嘛
Um, can I help you?
你忘记带笔记本了
You forgot your notebook.
哦 非常感谢你
Oh, thank you so much.
我确实需要它
I actually need this.
你没有偷偷看过吧
Um, hope you didn't read it.
- 不 当然没有  - 好好 别紧张
- No, of course not. - Oh, no,
我只是在开玩笑 我的字迹很乱 你肯定也看不懂
I'm just kidding. It's just chicken scratch.
等等 艾琳
Wait. Eileen.
就是问一下
I don't mean to be forward,
如果你今天晚上没什么计划的话
and, um, you probably have other plans already,
我们能去喝一杯吗
but, um, can I take you to a drink tonight?
在这个该死的镇上 我一个人都不认识
I don't know anyone in this darn town,
如果您愿意的话 我很乐意请你喝杯鸡尾酒
and I'd love to treat you to a cocktail if you're game.
- 好啊  - 可以吗
- Okay. - Okay?
我没有打乱你的计划吧
I've twisted your arm?
镇上最好的马提尼是哪家的
So, uh, who makes the best martini in town?
- 也许是奥哈拉的  - 奥哈拉吗
- Maybe O'Hara's? - O'Hara's.
实际上 这是镇上唯一的酒吧
It's actually the only bar in town.
不会 这就已经很好了
No, O'Hara's is good.
晚上七点见
See you at 7:00?
叮叮（很热情地要去某个地方的习语） 是这么说的吗
With bells on? Is that the expression?
♪ 我知道你被别人♪
♪ I know you've been hurt♪
♪ 伤害了♪
♪ By someone else♪
♪ 从你走路的样子♪
♪ I can tell by the way♪
♪ 我就能看出来 ♪
♪ You carry yourself♪
♪ 如果你愿意♪
♪ But if you let me♪
♪ 我会这么做♪
♪ Here's what I'll do♪
♪ 我会照顾你的♪
♪ I'll take care of you♪
♪ 我...我爱过也失去过♪
♪ I... I've loved and lost♪
♪ 和你一样♪
♪ The same as you♪
♪ 所以你看 我知道♪
♪ So you see, I know♪
♪ 你所经历的 ♪
♪ Just what you've been through ♪
♪ 但如果你允许我♪
♪ But if you'll let me♪
♪ 我会这么做♪
♪ Here's what I'll do♪
♪ 哦 我只是要照顾你 ♪
♪ Oh, I just got to take care of you ♪
♪ 你永远不必担心 ♪
♪ You won't ever have to worry ♪
♪ 你永远不必哭泣♪
♪ You won't ever have to cry♪
♪ 因为我会在你身边 ♪
♪ For I'll be there beside you ♪
♪ 擦干你哭泣的眼睛♪
♪ To dry your weeping eyes♪
♪ 那么 亲爱的♪
♪ So, darling♪
♪ 告诉我♪
♪ Tell me♪
♪ 你愿意吗♪
♪ That you'll be true♪
♪ 不带着一丝疑问...♪
♪ For there is no doubt...♪
- 嗨 - 哦 艾琳
- Hi. - Oh, Eileen.
嗨
Hi.
快坐
Please, please, please, sit.
你要什么
Um, what are you having?
来杯啤酒就行了
Uh, I'll have a beer, I guess.
啤酒啊
A beer? Oh.
嗨 艾琳
Hi, Eileen.
很高兴见到你 亲爱的
Good to see you, hon.
然后呢 亲爱的
What's next, sweetheart?
哦 你真的是
Um, well... Oh, my stars.
彻底被冻僵了
You're absolutely frozen.
嗯 请来一杯啤酒 再来点儿威士忌
Um, one beer, please, and maybe a little whiskey
暖暖我的女孩儿 怎么样
to warm up my girl. What say, huh?
亲爱的 你看起来非常迷人
My, you look very glamorous.
只是一件旧衣服
It's just an old dress.
我来吧
May I?
你呢 亲爱的 再来一杯马提尼吗
How about you, sweetheart? Another martini?
没错 再来一杯 谢谢
Love one. Thank you.
这次就不要把橄榄弄进去了
Maybe let's hold the olives this time.
我还以为这个地方很难找
I thought I'd have a hard time finding this place,
但是我还是找到了
but here it is.
你还好吗
You feeling all right?
嗯 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
呃 我的车出了点问题
Uh, there's something wrong with my car,
开车的时候车窗得一直摇下来
so I have to drive with the windows down,
不然车里面就都是烟
or else it fills with smoke.
天啊
Oh, you're kidding.
这也太糟糕了
That sounds absolutely awful.
不能让你老公帮你弄一下吗
Can't you get your husband to fix that for you?
哦 不 我还没结婚
Oh, no, I'm not married.
我一直单身
I've always been single.
哈哈 如果我身边有什么男人的话
And when I do have a guy around,
那也就是简单玩儿玩儿 不会太久
it's just for fun, and it's brief.
我从来不会让什么人在我身边停留太久
No, I never stay anywhere long with anything.
有点像我的权宜之计
Sort of my modus vivendi
或者是有点儿病态吧 这得看是什么人
or my pathology, depending on who I'm talking to.
你在摩尔黑德工作了多久了
How long have you worked at Moorehead?
三四年了
Three or four years.
本来应该只是暂时的
Uh, it was only supposed to be temporary,
当时是我母亲生病了 所以我才回来待了一阵子
while I moved back for a bit while my mother was sick,
结果她没有扛过去 所以…
and then she died, so...
我一直在监狱里工作 时间过得真快
I've been at the prison, and time's just flown by.
天啊
Oh, God.
那可不是个消磨时间的好地方
Prison is no place for time to fly by.
还有你妈妈的死
And your mother dying.
这对你而言真的很难 你还这么小
That's a lot for a young lady.
嗯 当时我24岁
Ah. 24.
现在你一定很渴望回到那个时候吧 不是吗
Then you must be eager to get back out there. Are you?
其实我也是个孤儿
You know, um, I'm an orphan, too.
是我叔叔在西部把我养大的
My uncle raised me out West.
那是个阳光普照的地方
Where the sun shines.
我都不知道你们是怎么扛过来的
I don't understand how you all do it here,
一个又一个的冬天
winter after winter.
怎么说 真的挺毛骨悚然的
It's positively creepy. I don't know.
我对新英格兰有一种奇怪的依恋
I'm in a sort of strange love affair with New England.
我喜欢它 但我也讨厌它
I love it, but I also hate it.
这里的一切都很真实 不是吗
Things feel very real here, don't they?
希望没有...
Sort of there's no...
...那些不切实际的东西
...imagination.
没有悲伤 也没有那些幻想
There's no sentimentality or fantasy.
这里...真的无处可藏了
There's... there's just nowhere to hide.
抱歉
Sorry.
我喝太多了
I've had too much to drink.
我一喝多就是这样 滔滔不绝的
I tend to talk when I've had too much to drink.
还行
It's all right.
总比话少好
Mm, it's better than talking too little.
你今天看到李·波尔克了吗
Did you see Lee Polk today?
呃…
Uh...
她有跟你说话吗
Did she say anything to you?
波尔克夫人吗
Mrs. Polk?
她只是心烦意乱
She was just upset.
那些妈妈们总是这样
Those mothers are always upset.
你觉得她像个愤怒的女人吗
Did she seem like an angry woman to you?
我不知道 呃...
I don't know. Uh...
这里每个人都多少有点儿愤怒
everyone's kind of angry here.
这就是马萨诸塞州
It's Massachusetts.
嗯 我在哈佛大学有一位教授
Well, I had this professor at Harvard.
他很聪明 但也很难搞
He was brilliant, but very difficult.
他在囚犯身上做了个实验
Uh, he did this-- these experiments on prisoners
用来研究迷幻药对累犯的影响
studying the effects of psychedelics on recidivism.
我不同意他的方法
Now, I don't agree with his methods,
没有什么灵丹妙药
there is no magic pill,
但是...但是如果你能让罪犯们自己吐露出真相 然后感受它
but... but you can set people free...
这样他们就能获得一种类似自由的解脱
...if you can get them to tell the truth, to feel it.
这就是我尝试做的
That's what I want to do.
秘密和谎言
Secrets and lies.
我跟你说 小娃娃…
I tell you, doll...
…有些家庭就是这么病态 扭曲
...some families are so sick, so twisted,
唯一的出路就是有人死掉
the only way out's for someone to die.
你不这么觉得吗
Don't you think?
嘿 你叫什么名字来着
Hey! What'd you say your name was?
谁 我吗
Who, me?
嗯 是啊 我们刚刚还在说
Ah, yeah. W-We was just saying
你看起来很眼熟
that you look so familiar.
你有演过电影吗 还是别的什么
Are you in the movies or something?
怎么会 我在男子监狱工作
Hardly. I work at the boys' prison.
- 啊 - 我是艾琳
- Ah. - I'm Eileen,
这是我的朋友瑞贝卡
and this is my friend, Rebecca.
她是一位心理学家
She's a psychologist.
别害羞 瑞贝卡
Don't be shy, Rebecca.
我们这些男孩又不会咬人
These boys won't bite.
如果你想让我们这么做
Not unless you ask us to.
这是杰瑞 不用理他
This is Jerry. You can ignore him.
他已经结婚了
He's married.
杰瑞 你的牙怎么了
What happened to your teeth, Jerry?
你跟你老婆吵架了吗
You get into a fight with your old lady?
就是这样 他老婆的左拳跟乔·弗雷泽一样
That's it. His wife's got a left like Joe Frazier.
不 不 他…他只是在冰上滑倒了
Nah, nah. He... he slipped on the ice.
反正我还要去种牙
I'm gonna grow some new ones, though.
这样就行了
Just need a few more of these.
为杰瑞和他的新牙干杯
Cheers to that. To Jerry and his new teeth.
♪ 你一定非常想要它♪
♪ You've gotta want it bad♪
♪ 渴望已经融入了你的血液 ♪
♪ If that guy's got into your blood ♪
要跳舞吗 瑞贝卡
Feel like dancing, Rebecca?
我们俩吗
With you?
是啊
Yeah.
♪ 你的真心♪
♪ The very heart of you♪
♪ 让你想要呼吸
♪ Makes you want to breathe
♪ 接下来就这么做
♪ Here's the thing to do
♪ 告诉他你永远不会离开他 ♪
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him ♪
♪ 告诉他你永远爱他 ♪
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him ♪
♪ 告诉他 告诉他 告诉他 现在就告诉他 ♪
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now ♪
♪ 我知道一些关于爱的事
♪ I know something about love
♪ 你必须得表现出来
♪ You gotta show it and
♪ 让他看到头顶的月亮 ♪
♪ Make him see the moon up above ♪
♪ 去吧 就这么做♪
♪ Out and get him .Do, do-do
♪ 如果你想让他永远在你身边 ♪
♪ If you want him to be always by your side ♪
♪ 如果你想让他只想着你 ♪
♪ If you want him to only think of you ♪
♪ 告诉他你永远不会离开他 ♪
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him ♪
♪ 告诉他你永远爱他 ♪
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him ♪
♪ 告诉他 告诉他 告诉他 现在就告诉他 ♪
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now ♪
♪ 自从世界诞生以来
♪ Ever since the world began
♪ 男人就是这样
♪ It's been that way for man
♪ 还有女人...
♪ And women...
♪ 唇齿之间
♪ The touch of your lips
♪ 在我身边
♪ Next to mine
♪ 让我兴奋
♪ Gets me excited
♪ 我的感觉很棒
♪ Makes me feel fine
♪ 抚摸你的手
♪ The touch of your hand
♪ 还有你甜蜜的问候
♪ Your sweet hello
♪ 你内心燃起的火焰
♪ The fire inside you
♪ 当你紧紧拥抱我时 ♪
♪ When you're holding me close ♪
♪ 你的爱如此温暖温柔 ♪
♪ Your love so warm and tender ♪
♪ 你的残酷无比神圣
♪ Oh. The thrill is so divine
♪ 所有的一切
♪ It is all these things
♪ 都让我更渴望你
♪ That make you mine
♪ 如果你要离开
♪ If you would leave
♪ 我肯定会死
♪ I surely would die
♪ 哪怕是迟了十分钟 ♪
♪ When you were ten minutes late ♪
♪ 我都会难过
♪ I started to cry
♪ 啊啊啊啊
♪ Ah, ah, ah
♪ 我真的很需要你
♪ I've got it bad
♪ 但没关系
♪ But it's all right
♪ 只要你在
♪ As long as you're here
♪ 每天晚上...
♪ Every night...
你让我想起荷兰画中的一个女孩
You remind me of a girl in a Dutch painting.
你有一张不寻常的脸
You have a strange face.
朴素 但是...
It's plain, but...
...却很迷人
...fascinating.
有一种美丽的...
It has a beautiful...
...波澜
...turbulence.
我很喜欢
I love it.
我打赌你一定有过辉煌的梦想
I bet you have brilliant dreams.
梦想着另一个世界
I bet you dream of other worlds.
也许你还会梦见我还有我早晨悔恨的样子
Maybe you'll dream of me and my morning remorse,
这是肯定的
which is certain.
我不应该喝酒
I shouldn't drink,
但我也喝了
but I do.
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿 桑迪 给我一杯马提尼酒还有火
Hey, Sandy, can I get a martini and some matches?
最好小心一点 艾琳
Better be careful, Eileen.
我可不想跟你爸爸起什么冲突
I don't want any trouble with your dad.
他不会的
My dad's not gonna cause any trouble.
爸爸 爸爸
Dad. Dad.
让我进去
Dad, can you let me in?
妈的
Shit.
嘿 老爸
Hey, Dad!
钥匙呢
Can I have the keys?
钥匙在哪里
Can I please have the keys?
除非你从头到尾读完那本书
No, you may not have the keys.
不然肯定没戏
Not until you read that book from cover to cover.
我要听清每一个字
I want to hear every word.
你把钥匙放哪儿了
Where'd you put the keys?
好好找个地方读书吧 艾琳
Make yourself comfortable, Eileen.
在读完最后一个字之前 你哪儿也去不了
You're not going anywhere till you read the last word.
爸爸 这太荒谬了 我还要去上班
Dad, this is ridiculous. I need to go to work.
你整个晚上都在外面
Out all night.
还差点把车撞坏了
Nearly crashed the car.
跟你自己的呕吐物睡在一起
Sleeping in your own sick,
现在你想起来要上班了
and now you're worried about getting to work on time?
我都不能直视你 我觉得很丢人
I can hardly look at you, I'm so ashamed.
雾都孤儿都会知道感激这个家
Oliver Twist would be grateful for this home,
但是你呢 艾琳
but you, Eileen,
你就是垃圾 艾琳 垃圾
you're trash, Eileen, just trash.
我只不过是下班之后跟一个女生出去了
All I did was go out with a girl from work.
是这样吗
You went out with a girl from work?
你觉得我有这么好骗吗
Do I look like I was born yesterday?
那个男的是谁啊
Who is he? Huh?
我只是想知道他是谁
Who is this boy? I just want to know who he is
趁着你还没被搞大肚子 把灵魂卖给撒旦之前
before you get knocked up and sell your soul to Satan.
你能把钥匙给我吗
Can you just give me the keys?!
我要迟到了
Please! I'll be late!
你穿成这样哪儿也去不了
You're not going anywhere dressed like that.
我是认真地 艾琳 你怎么敢的
I mean, really, Eileen, how dare you?
那是你母亲参加我父亲葬礼时穿的衣服
That's the dress your mother wore to my father's funeral.
我没有尊重我们任何一个人
You got no respect for anyone.
马上换掉
Get changed.
别让任何人看到你穿着这套衣服
I don't want anyone seeing you in that getup.
他们会以为我已经死了
They'll think I'm dead.
嘿 邓洛普小姐
Ah. Miss Dunlop?
我能跟你说句话吗
May I, um, may I have a word?
哦 天啊
Oh, Jesus.
是关于你父亲的
It's about your father.
他吗 去吧 他就在里面
Him? Go talk to him. He's inside.
是关于他的枪的
It's about his gun.
肯定很精彩
This oughta be good.
说吧 巴克
Pray tell, Buck.
呃 是昨天
Uh, yesterday,
我们收到了邻居的一些投诉
we got several complaints from neighbors,
还有学校的康尼小姐的投诉
from Miss Connie down at the school,
呃 邓洛普先生
that, uh, Chief Dunlop
就坐在朝北的窗户那边
was sitting in that north-facing window
然后用枪指着
and, uh, pointing his weapon
放学回家的孩子们
at children walking home from school.
已经同意把这交给你照管
He has agreed to relinquish the property into your care.
只要你保证不对他用的话
As long as you promise not to use it on him.
他的原话
His words.
可以吗
May I come in?
你想把那把枪当装饰品挂在我身上吗
Want to hang it on me like an ornament?
我确信邓洛普小姐
I'm sure that Miss Dunlop
会好好保养这把武器的 先生
will take excellent care of the weapon, sir.
巴克 你也看到了 她对待一切事情都是这样
As she does with all things, Buck, as you can see.
♪ 圣诞节到了
♪ It's Christmastime
♪ 我想见圣诞老人
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus
♪ 什么 什么 什么
♪ What? What? What?
♪ 是的 现在是圣诞节
♪ Yes, it's Christmastime
♪ 我想见圣诞老人
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus
♪ 什么 什么 什么
♪ What? What? What?
♪ 他还有要给我的孩子的礼物呢
♪ Gonna ask him for my baby
♪ 这不是个好理由吗 ♪
♪ Ain't that a real good cause? ♪
你得告诉我都是谁
Let me know which ones.
当然 我会等的
Sure. I'll hold.
看看谁来了
Ah, look what the cat dragged in.
下午好 艾琳
Good afternoon, Eileen.
你看起来像雏菊一样清新 跟往常一样
You look fresh as a daisy, as always.
我的车出了问题
I had car trouble.
当然 我肯定会相信你的
Yeah, I believe the trouble part.
快到圣诞节了 你能让我休息一下吗
It's almost Christmas. Can you give me a break?
不行 赶紧工作吧
No. Get to work.
我需要波尔克的档案
Okay. I need the Polk file.
嗯
Yeah.
我以为她已经拿到手里了
I think Dr. St. John has it.
很好 是的
Perfect. Yeah, I'm afraid that one
恐怕要等到假期之后了
will have to wait till after the holidays.
我们要来一位新医生了
We have a new doctor on staff,
因为那位她不遵守程序
and, uh, apparently she doesn't follow procedures.
- 她今天没来吗  - 来了又走了
- She's not in today? - Been and gone.
圣诞节之后还会回来的
She's gonna be back after Christmas.
是的 我会的
Yeah. Will do.
好吧 谢谢
All right, then. Thank you.
拜
Bye-bye.
你这是要去哪儿啊
Where do you think you're going?
卫生间
The infirmary.
我觉得有点儿想吐
I think something's going around.
你怎么在到处乱晃呢
You look like you've been going around.
她是个酒鬼
She's a boozer.
爸
Dad?
你能听到我说话吗
Dad, can you hear me?
爸爸 你能听到我说话吗
- 你在那儿做什么 - 我需要我的枪
- What were you doing up there? - I need my gun.
- 坐起来 - 有人在追我
- Sit up. - It's after me.
没人在追你
Nobody's after you.
坐起来 坐起来
Sit up. Sit up.
乔安妮
Joanie.
是你吗乔安妮
That you, Joanie?
嘿
Hey.
乔安妮 乔安妮
Joanie. Joanie.
乔安妮
Joanie.
爸爸
Dad.
不用大惊小怪的 乔安妮
Quit your fussing, Joanie.
我们已经给他缝了伤口
We stitched him up,
排除了脑震荡的可能
and I don't think he has a concussion,
但他的血液酒精浓度
but his blood alcohol level
有0.17
is point one-seven.
肝硬化的指标很危险 而且还浑身都是淤青
His liver's enlarged, and he's covered in bruises.
我不是要怪你 亲爱的 但是 呃…
I'm not blaming you, honey, but, uh...
好 当然
Yeah, sure.
但是到底是谁让他这样啊
Hey, who's letting him live like this?
我不知道 我妈妈去世了 他现在也没有工作
I don't know. My mom died, and he doesn't have a job.
他还能做什么
What else is he supposed to do?
可是总不能整天喝酒吧
Yeah, there are men who don't drink all day.
我知道
I know that.
听着 我知道这对你来说很难 但是 呃…
Look, I know this is hard for you, but, uh...
如果他不喝酒的话 他只是有可能活不下去了
if he stops drinking, he might die,
但如果他继续喝酒 那他肯定就没命了
but if he keeps drinking, it'll definitely kill him.
除此之外我也不知道还能跟你说什么了
I don't know what else to say to you.
坐下 爸爸
Sit down, Dad.
医生告诉我你会死的
The doctor told me you're gonna die.
怎么 他是不会死吗
Oh, like he's not?
他说 如果你如果再这样喝酒
He said, if you keep drinking like this,
那些酒精真的会害死你的
it'll kill you.
去他的吧
Screw him.
他们就是在那家医院杀了你的母亲
You know they killed your mother at that hospital.
他们欠我的可不仅仅是缝个针这么简单
They owe me more than stitches.
你能往后靠吗
Can you lean back?
当然
Course I can lean back.
难不成我连怎么睡觉都不会了吗
You don't think I know how to go to bed?
得了 我还是要喝一杯
Well, I need a drink.
爸爸
Dad!
反正我不要睡在这里
And anyway, I do not sleep here.
- 这里会闹鬼 - 求你了 爸爸
- It's haunted. - Please, Dad.
如果我给你一瓶酒的话 你能躺下吗
If I get you a bottle, will you lie down?
不 我想和我女儿喝一杯
No. I want to have a drink with my daughter.
你这几天不太一样了
You're different these days.
就快变得很有趣了
You're almost interesting.
你用工作赚的钱都去做什么了
What are you doing with all the money you make at work?
怎么不给自己买件衣服呢
Why don't you ever buy your own clothes?
我还记得那件外套
I remember that coat.
还记得你妈妈...
I remember your mother...
我穿起来怎么样
How does it look on me?
嗯 反正你妈妈穿那件外套看起来很漂亮
Well, your mother looked beautiful in that coat.
是她从精神病院出来的时候
I bought it for her to wear
我买给她穿的
when she got out of the bughouse.
我一直爱着你的母亲
I always loved your mother.
不管你是怎么看的
No matter what you thought it looked like,
我一直都爱着她
I always loved her.
我知道他们都是怎么说我的
And I know what people say about me.
他们说是我逼疯她的 因为我很难搞
They say I made her crazy 'cause I'm a hard-ass.
我可能确实朝她喊过几次
And I may have yelled a few times,
但是她总会原谅我
but she always forgave me.
因为我们彼此相爱
Because we loved each other.
爱会让你疯狂 艾琳
Love will make you crazy, Eileen.
你可能永远都不会明白这一点
You'll probably never understand that.
为什么
Why?
有些人...
Some people...
他们才是真正的人
they're the real people.
就像是那些电影里你正在看着的人
Like in a movie, they're the ones you're watching.
他们才是主角
They're the ones making moves.
而其他人...
And the other people...
...他们只是用来当配角 填补空白用的
...they're just there filling the space,
你会觉得这是理所当然的
and you take 'em for granted.
还会觉得这不是很容易吗
You think, "They're easy."
他们就是这样 拿一分 留一分
Take a penny, leave a penny.
那就是你 艾琳
That's you, Eileen.
你就跟他们一样
You're one of them.
你在干什么 不用锁
What are you doing? You don't gotta lock it.
走吧
Let's go.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
快点 太冷了
Come on. It's cold out here.
快点儿
Come on. Hurry up.
把门打开
Open the door.
真他妈重
Fucking heavy.
把酒拿来
Give me my fucking drink.
艾琳
Eileen!
什么了 爸爸
What, Dad?
电话响了
Phone rang.
有个女人找你
Some woman looking for you.
你说了什么吗
What'd you say?
没有
Nothing.
我什么都没说
I know nothing. I said nothing.
你好
Hello.
你好 圣诞天使
Hello, Christmas angel.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca?
听着 我只是想到你
Look, I was just thinking of you,
好吧 我也不知道
and, well, I-I don't know
平安夜你有什么计划
what you're planning for Christmas Eve,
也许你愿意过来
but I thought maybe you'd like to come over.
我们可以放一些唱片
There are some records we could play,
如果一切顺利的话 也可以跳舞
and maybe dance again if all goes well.
当然 除非你有更好的提议
Unless you have a better offer, of course.
不会有比这更好的了
I don't have a better offer.
- 所以你会来吗 - 是的
- So you'll come? - Yeah.
我把地址给你
Let me give you the address.
稍等
Okay. Hold on.
枫树街32号
It's 32 Maple Street.
今晚见
So see you later.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
♪ 唇齿之间的触感
♪ The touch of your lips
♪ 在我身边
♪ Next to mine
♪ 让我兴奋
♪ Gets me excited
♪ 让我感觉很好 哦 哦
♪ Makes me feel fine. Oh, oh
♪ 抚摸着你的手
♪ The touch of your hand
♪ 你甜蜜的问候
♪ Your sweet hello
♪ 你内心的火焰 .
♪ The fire inside you
♪ 当你紧紧拥抱我时 ♪
♪ When you're holding me close ♪
♪ 你的爱如此温暖
♪ Your love so warm
♪ 又温柔...
♪ And tender...
你来啦
Y-You're here.
真是圣诞节的奇迹
It's a Christmas miracle.
抱歉我花了这么长时间
Sorry it took me so long.
我觉得那只猫着魔了
I think that cat's possessed.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
太贴心了
Oh. Aren't you a peach?
请进 快请进
Come in! Come in.
艾琳 嗯
Eileen, um,
抱歉 这个地方太乱了
I'm sorry the place is such a mess.
我实在...我是说 我有试着整理一下
I-I haven't... I mean, I tried to clean it up a bit,
但这真的超出了我的能力范围
but it's just beyond me.
希望你不会觉得不舒服
I hope it doesn't make you uncomfortable.
我们把酒打开吧
Let's open this wine.
快坐 快坐
Uh, sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
希望你没有开的太久 会很远吗
I hope you didn't have to drive far. Was it far?
不会 就是随便开开
Uh, no. I drive all over the place.
把外套给我吧
Let me take your coat.
- 谢谢 - 天啊
- Thanks. - Oh, my.
摸起来真舒服
It's so nice and soft.
这是我母亲的
It's my mother's.
哦 她一定是一位真正优雅的女士
Well, uh, she must have been a real classy lady
才能有你这么优秀的女儿
to have such a classy daughter.
她确实如此
She was something of a clotheshorse, actually.
希望是你喜欢的那种
I hope it's a kind you like.
肯定很好吃
Oh. I'm sure it's delicious.
喝酒也不错
Drink sounds nice, actually.
我来找找开瓶器在哪里
Let's see where the corkscrew's hiding.
呃 你知道吧
Uh, you know,
我最近实在是太忙了
I have just been so busy lately
放哪里去了呢...
that I can't seem to remember where the...
肯定就在这摊东西里面
But it's got to be here under all this mess, right?
你知道吗
You know what?
有个很手巧的年轻的哲学博士以前教过我一招儿
A very handy young PhD student once taught me a trick
在你被困的情况下要怎么打开一个瓶子
for how to open a bottle if you're ever stranded
还没有开瓶器
without a corkscrew.
哲学家们才是最大的酒鬼
Philosophers are always the biggest drunks.
虽然他本来就有点儿可爱
Although he was kind of cute.
尤金·亨德森 哈佛大学
Eugene Henderson, Harvard.
我不知道你还能这样呢
I had no idea you could do that.
很棒的一招儿
That was a great trick.
现在需要的就是酒杯了
Now we need some glasses.
敬艾琳 我的圣诞救星
So to Eileen, my Christmas savior.
救星吗
Savior?
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
成为我的朋友
Well, you're being a friend.
这还不够吗 干杯
That's everything. Cheers.
天哪 太可怕了
God, that's awful.
不 那...
No. That's a...
味道好浓
...punch of flavor.
这就是席拉（一种葡萄酒）
That's what a Syrah is.
希望你没有花太多钱
Hope you haven't spent too much on it.
敬...
To...
敬耶稣基督
To Jesus Christ.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你一个人住在这里吗
Do you live here alone?
不
No.
哦 是的
Oh, uh, sure.
我 呃...不 我不能忍受有室友
I, uh... No, I can't have roommates.
我 嗯 我喜欢独处
I, um, I like my own space.
我也能很高兴
I still like to have fun,
而且 呃 我还能弄出很大的声音
and, uh, I can make a lot of noise.
还有把一切都弄乱 你也看到了
And, uh, I can make a mess, as you can see,
对了 还可以随心所欲地放歌儿
but, uh, I can play music as loud as I want to.
还能...
I can...
随心所欲地尖叫
I can scream as loud as I want to.
我也是
I can't stand roommates, either.
上大学的时候 我都必须锁门…
In college, I had to lock my door...
是啊 你上大学的时候
Oh, that's right. You were in college.
你学的什么
What'd you study?
就是些必修课
Just the required courses.
嗯 如果我没有辍学的话
Um, if I hadn't left,
反正我最后可能也会做秘书
I probably would have ended up a secretary anyway.
艾琳 这不是你真正的样子
Eileen, you're not really a secretary.
默里夫人和史蒂文斯夫人 她们才是这样
Mrs. Murray and Mrs. Stevens, they're secretaries,
因为她们总是别人说什么就做什么
'cause they do what they're told,
这也是她们过得这么悲惨还有令人讨厌的原因
and that's why they're miserable and nasty.
但我相信 你的人生还有美好的未来
But you, you got a big life ahead of you, I'm sure.
好的 希望我的人生不会就到此为止了
Okay. I'm not a real secretary.
当然不会
No, you're not.
因为你很聪明
'Cause you're smart.
而且你也很好奇 不是吗
And you're curious, aren't you?
我在学校的表现从来都不是很好
Mm, I never really did very good in school,
所以我觉得自己只是一个普通人
so I'm just kind of average, I think.
哦 别这么说 艾琳
Oh, don't say that, Eileen.
永远不要这么说 你...
Never say that. Do you...?
你真以为自己很普通吗
You really think you're a normal person?
普通怎么了
Normal how?
不过我确实是一个糟糕的女主人
I really am a bad hostess.
也许我们 呃...
Maybe we'll, uh...
吃点儿东西吧 这样才像样
We'll feel better if we eat something.
我挺好的
I feel fine.
我能用下你的洗手间吗
Can I use your bathroom?
当然
Sure.
就在楼上
Just up the stairs.
是另一个门 右边的
It's the other door, on the right.
抱歉
Sorry.
有什么好抱歉的
What do you have to be sorry for?
来嘛 吃吧
Go on. Go on. Eat. Eat. Yeah.
还有那个腌黄瓜
Have a pickle, too.
为什么我们还需要什么小奶酪刀
Why do we need a little, uh, cheese knife?
就为了不弄脏手
To keep our hands clean?
不 这一切都很荒谬
No. It's all ridiculous.
一切都是
Everything is.
所有这些愚蠢的传统
All these stupid traditions,
就跟圣诞节那个时候的监狱还有那个典狱长
like the-the warden and his prison at Christmas.
什​​么意思
What do you mean?
我试图解释事情需要怎么改变
I've tried explaining how things need to change,
但他只关心
but all he cares about
那些男孩儿晚上在牢房里自慰的时候
is whether or not the boys are gonna think about me
性幻想的对象是不是我
while they molest themselves in their cells at night.
但愿不会
God forbid.
摩尔黑德有严格的
There's a strict
禁止手淫的规定
no masturbation policy at Moorehead.
这在监狱是违法的
It's illegal to get off in prison.
你知道 对吧
You know that, right?
好像那些有性高潮的人
As if that's the downfall of civilization,
就是一种文明的衰败一样
people having orgasms.
你不能指望男人来解决任何问题
You can't count on men to fix anything.
人们羞于面对自己的欲望
People are so ashamed of their desires,
尤其是男人
especially men.
艾琳……
Eileen...
...你现在可能已经知道了
...as you can probably tell by now,
我的生活方式与大多数人都不太一样
I live a little differently than most people.
不 你的房子...很好
No, your house i-is nice.
- 不是说这个  - 很舒服
- No. - It's cozy.
我说的不是房子 我是说...
I don't mean the house. I mean...
我有自己的想法
I have my own ideas.
也许我们有些想法是一样的
Maybe you and I share some of those ideas.
有哪些呢
What kind of ideas do we share?
我可以跟你说吗
May I confide in you?
当然
Of course.
是关于李·波尔克的
It's about Lee Polk.
- 是吗  - 是的
- It is? - Yes.
你说说 亲爱的...
Tell me, honey...
…什么会让一个人想要杀死自己的父亲呢
...what would make a person want to kill their father?
每个人都想杀死自己的父亲
Everybody wants to kill their father.
不 不是这样的 谁告诉你的
No, they don't. Who told you that?
真的 想想吧 艾琳
Really, think about it, Eileen.
因为李可是偷偷溜进了他父母的卧室
Because Lee snuck into his parents' bedroom
还是在半夜...
in the middle of the night...
...砍断了他父亲的喉咙
...hacked through his father's throat
就用一把旧菜刀
with an old kitchen knife,
而且在他的胸部那里砍了好几刀
and stabbed him in the chest repeatedly.
他的母亲声说她还以为有人入室盗窃
His mother claimed she thought there'd been a break-in.
遇到这种事你怎么睡得着
How do you sleep through something like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你也不知道 所以我才叫她来
You don't. That's why I called her in.
你当时也在那里
I mean, you were there.
那个可怜的男孩几乎不敢看她 所以…
The poor boy could barely look at her, so...
所以后来我就直截了当地问他
so afterwards, I just asked him point-blank.
我说...
I said...
我问他他爸爸都对他做了什么
I said, "What'd your father do to you?"
"你为什么要这样对待你父亲的尸体"
"What made you want to do that to your father's body?"
他没花了几分钟就全都说了
And he spilled it all in a matter of minutes.
以前从来没有人费心去问过他
Nobody had ever bothered to ask him before.
没有人想过还要问他
No one had thought to ask.
你不想知道吗
Wouldn't you want to know?
难道你不好奇吗
Wouldn't you be curious?
好奇
Yes.
你想知道吗
Do you want to know?
是的
Yes.
艾琳 你永远不能告诉任何人 你明白吗
Eileen, you can never tell anyone. Do you understand?
你明白...答应我
You understa... Promise me.
我保证
Promise.
你首先需要知道的是
The first thing you need to know,
这不是我的家
this isn't my house.
这就是波尔克的家
This is the Polk house.
波克夫人被我绑在楼下
I have Mrs. Polk tied up downstairs.
艾琳 艾琳
Eileen. Eileen.
艾琳
Eileen.
艾琳 别走
Eileen, please wait.
艾琳 拜托了
Eileen, please.
我以为我自己就可以的 艾琳
I thought I could do this alone, Eileen.
请不要走 艾琳
Please don't go. Eileen!
别走 拜托了
Please, don't go. Please.
我以为你邀请我过来是因为你喜欢我
I thought you invited me over here 'cause you liked me.
哦 当然是这样
Oh, I do.
当然是这样 抱歉 抱歉 艾琳
I do. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Please, Eileen.
拜托 拜托 艾琳 请给我一点时间
Just pl-please, Eileen. Just give me a moment.
让我解释一下
Please just let me explain.
我需要...
I need...
我需要一个朋友
I need a friend.
我昨天下午来过这里
I came here yesterday afternoon
跟波尔克夫人谈了话
to talk to Mrs. Polk.
我说我看得出来她跟李会面后
I said I could see that she was upset
一直很沮丧
after our meeting with Lee,
我问她有什么想跟我说的吗
was there anything she wanted to discuss.
她说没什么 所以我...
She said, "Nothing," so I...
我追问她
I pressed her.
我把李告诉我的话告诉了她
I told her what Lee had told me.
她向我吐口水 说我变态了
She spat at me, called me the pervert,
然后称她的丈夫为圣人
then called her husband a saint,
我留下了我的名片 让她考虑一下
and I left my card, told her to think about it.
我知道她不会打电话来 然后我就离开了
I knew she wouldn't call. Then I left.
现在 我整晚都无法入睡
Now, I couldn't sleep last night.
因为我...
'Cause I...
一直在想李跟我说的话
I couldn't stop thinking about what Lee had told me,
他父亲做的那些事
what his father had done,
以及他的母亲是如何纵容这一切的
and how his mother had let it happen.
我都不记得自己是怎么开车过来的 我很生气
I don't even remember the drive over here, I was so angry.
我就把她挤到一边
Suddenly I was pushing past her,
质问她怎么能这么做
saying, "How could you do it?
你怎么能纵容这一切呢
How could you be complicit in such torture?"
她恶狠狠地回绝我
And she snapped.
她还打了我 你看
She attacked me. See?
看到了吗
See?
所以我只能还手保护自己
So I defended myself.
我们吵架了 我...我不知道发生了什么
We fought, and I... I don't know what happened,
但不知怎么的 我们从楼梯上摔到了地下室
but somehow we fell down the stairs to the basement.
我以为她会杀了我
I-I thought she was gonna kill me,
所以我用椅子打了她 然后把她绑了起来
so I hit her with a chair and tied her up.
我试图理性地跟她说话
I tried to talk to her rationally,
跟她解释我是来帮助李的
to explain that I was here to help Lee,
如果她允许的话 我也可以帮助她
that-that I could help her, too, if she'd let me,
但…但她只是不停地尖叫
but... but she just kept screaming
说...我绑架了她 她的丈夫是一名警察
that-that I'd kidnapped her and her husband was a cop
她说我这是要蹲监狱的
and I was gonna go to jail.
我在卫生间里发现了一些可待因（用鸦片制成的止痛镇咳药）
So I found some codeine in a bathroom,
我给她吃了为了让她安静下来
and got her to be quiet.
然后我就给你打了电话
Then I called you.
你也知道 这里我谁都不认识
Because, as you can see, I'm in a bit of a pinch.
我能怎么办
What can I do?
我需要波尔克夫人承认
I need Mrs. Polk to confess,
我需要一名证人 二对一
and I need a witness, two against one.
你明白吗
You understand?
哦 我不能进监狱
Oh, I can't go to jail.
好的
Okay.
好
在这儿等着
Wait here.
艾琳 等等...
Eileen. Wait...
不敢相信
It's incredible.
你怎么有枪
Why do you have that?
你为什么把它带到这里来
Why did you bring that around here?
我爸爸病了
My dad's sick.
拿起它 我看看你是怎么握枪的
Pick it up, and show me how you're gonna hold it.
非常好 艾琳
That's very good, Eileen.
好了
All right.
冷静点儿
Be cool.
告诉我们真相吧 波尔克夫人
Just tell us the truth, Mrs. Polk,
我们会放了你的
and we'll let you go free.
家人可以治愈一切
Families can heal.
你并不是一个失败的人 没有人是
You're not a lost cause. No one is.
嫁给这样的男人
It can't have been easy,
对你来说肯定不容易
being married to a man like that.
你肯定过得很艰难
You're obviously having a hard time.
你为什么不跟我们说说这间房子里都发生过什么
Why don't you tell us what happened in this house,
为什么你要纵容而且还帮助你的丈夫做那样的事
why you helped your husband do what he did?
这样就行了
And then we'll be even,
没有人会受伤 然后…
and we can all walk out of here, and...
我们可以想办法帮助李
and we can figure out how to help Lee.
他妈的给我解开 放开我
Fucking untie me! Untie me!
放开我
Let me out of here!
你这个疯女人 滚出我家
You crazy bitch, get out of my house!
你有大麻烦了 你以为你会...
You're in big trouble, you think you're gonna
- 逃过去吗 - 艾琳
- get away with this! - Eileen.
你会蹲很久的监狱
You're going to jail for a long time.
她到底在这里做什么
What the hell is she doing here?!
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我真的觉得你应该告诉我们真相
I really think you need to tell us the truth.
你他妈在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?!
如果你不说...
If you don't...
我们可以把你绑在这儿
we could leave you down here tied up,
没有人能找到你
no one to find you.
一个人如果没有食物和水
The human body can't live very long
是活不了太久的
without food and water.
而且你肯定还要上厕所
Sooner or later, you're gonna need to take a shit.
我想你只能拉在自己身上了
I guess you're just gonna have to shit yourself.
还有尿
And piss.
肯定不会很好受
It's not gonna feel very good.
我不怕你
I'm not scared of you.
我认识你
I know you.
我知道你爸爸是谁
I know who your dad is.
如果你认识我爸爸 那么你应该感到害怕
If you know my dad, then you oughta be scared.
是吗 害怕一个玩弄女人的醉鬼吗
Yeah? Scared of a womanizing, drunk piece of shit
大家都知道到底谁才是疯子
who everybody knows is batshit crazy?
你以为他自己没有问题吗
You think he didn't have problems of his own?
你以为他没有自己的小秘密 是吗
You think he didn't have secrets of his own, huh?
你觉得你妈妈不知道吗
You think your mom didn't know about 'em?
你以为...
Think it didn't...
我他妈要杀了你
I am going to fucking kill you
如果你还不说的话
if you don't start talking right now!
拜托
Please!
别杀我
Please, don't kill me.
只要你都招了 我就不会杀你
I won't have to kill you if you talk.
我不能
I can't.
不行 拜托了
No, please.
她也帮不了你 说吧
She's not gonna help you. Talk.
除非你坦白 否则我帮不了你
I can't help you unless you confess.
好吧
All right.
你赢了
You win.
当你结婚了
When you get married
还有了孩子...
and you have children...
结婚的时候你要宣誓
You take an oath when you get married
尊重并服从你的丈夫
to honor and obey your husband.
你不会明白这一点
You wouldn't understand that.
起初 我...
At first, I...
起初 我只是 我以为米奇
At first, I just, I thought Mitch
只是在睡梦中检查李
was just checking on him in his sleep,
所有父亲都会这样
you know, like any father would,
和他一样 他只是想确定一下
like he, he just wanted to be sure
他的儿子安然无恙地躺在床上
his son was safe and sound in bed.
有时我会...
Sometimes I'd...
...感觉他起床了
...feel him getting out of bed,
有时候我能感觉到他回来了
and sometimes I'd just feel him when he'd come back.
而他也会...
And he'd...
吻我或者...
kiss me or...
抱住我 然后……
hold me and...
你知道吗
You know?
自从李出生后
And we hadn't really been together
我们就没有过性生活了
since Lee'd been born.
但后来我...
But then I...
我发现自己下面有些感染
I started getting these infections down there.
我以为这是我的问题
I figured it was my fault.
后来我就想知道是不是米奇
And then I wondered if Mitch
把脏东西带回家的
had brought something home with him, you know?
然后有一次...
Then one time...
我半夜起来了
I got up in the middle of the night.
我也忘了是为什么
I don't remember why.
可能是要喝水吧 我也不记得了
Glass of water? I don't know.
也许这就是一场梦吧
I thought-I thought maybe it was a dream.
我...
I...
我走进去看了看
I went-I went and looked in.
我当时没有马上反应过来
It didn't dawn on me right away.
我发誓 我...
You know, I-I swear to you. I...
我是说...
I mean...
你也不会期望你的丈夫
You don't expect your husband's
会做这样的事情 对吧
gonna do something like that, you know?
反正没有人会相信的
I mean, nobody would believe it, anyway.
然后我…然后…
And then I... and then...
然后我想...
And then I figured...
然后我想 如果李都清理干净了..
And then I figured, if Lee was clean...
如果他干净的话
If he was clean,
睡前灌肠 洗个澡什么的...
an enema and a bath before bed...
...那对我们大家都好
...then it would be better for all of us.
确实如此
And it was.
我知道我在做什么 这...
I knew what I was doing, it wasn't...
这不对
it wasn't quite right.
我知道的 真的
I did know that. I did.
但你能告诉谁呢 你知道吗
But who do you tell? You know?
我能告诉谁
Who could I tell?
你只能这样了
I mean, you do the best you can.
你知道当你有了孩子之后会发生什么吗
You know what happens when you have children?
你丈夫看你的眼神再也不一样了
Your husband never looks at you the same.
但当他和李上床后
But after he went to bed with Lee,
他会来找我的
he'd come to me.
他好像是卸下了一个很大的负担
It was like a big burden had been lifted.
他是 他很放松
He was, he was relaxed.
他抱着我的感觉真好
It felt good, how he'd hold me.
那时他一定是爱我的
He loved me then.
他会在我耳边轻声细语然后吻我
He would whisper and kiss me.
以前也是这样…
It was the way it had been before...
…那时我们年轻 快乐 还彼此相爱
...when we were young and happy and in love.
那感觉很好
It felt good.
我错了吗…
Is that so wrong...
…我只是想要重温那时的感觉
...to want to feel like that?
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
你还年轻 你的心还没有被谁伤过
You're young, you haven't had your heart broken.
我在流血 我在流血
I'm bleeding! I'm bleeding!
帮帮我 帮帮我
Help me! Help me!
拜托 帮帮我
Please! Plea... Help me!
我在流血
I'm bleeding!
- 帮帮我 你们会后悔的  - 艾琳 帮帮我
- Help me! You'll be sorry! - Eileen, help me!
我会告诉所有人你们做了什么
I'll tell everyone what you've done!
- 艾琳  - 叫医生
- Eileen! - A doctor!
快去找医生
Get a doctor!
- 带我出去 - 艾琳 帮帮我
- Get me out of here! - Eileen, help me!
帮我
Help me!
不 不
No! No!
不
No.
不 不
No! No!
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
你为什么开枪打她
Why did you shoot her?
我很生气
I was upset.
我们现在该怎么办
What do we do now?
我们带她去我家
We take her to my house.
我爸总是会掏出枪
My dad's always whipping his gun out.
每个人都知道
Everyone knows it.
我们可以伪造成他在迷糊的时候开枪打中了她
We can make it look like he shot her in a blackout.
他只是个醉酒的混蛋 对吗
He's just a drunk piece of shit, right?
反正他最后不是疯掉就是死掉
He's gonna die anyway or go crazy.
医生是这么说的
The doctor said so.
我们带她一起走吧
So let's take her together and leave.
然后我们可以去纽约过新年…
Then we could go to New York for the New Year...
...就我们俩
...just the two of us.
我爱你
I love you.
没关系的
It's okay.
走吧
Come on.
好吧
All right.
你先去你父亲家
You go ahead to your father's house.
在那里等我
Wait for me there.
- 好 - 我会清理好里面
- Yeah. - I'll clean up inside.
我们不能留下任何证据
We can't leave any evidence behind.
- 我等你 - 我会快点的
- I'll be waiting. - I'll be quick.
艾琳
Eileen.
继续睡觉吧 爸爸
Go back to sleep, Dad.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
我只是要走了
I might just get on the road.
好吧
All right, then.
晚安
Good night.
翻译：霓虹狮子_